Nilpa K. Jhaveri

Education

MIT CSAIL xPro Certificate

Human Computer Interaction Computer Science & Al Lab May - June 2020

UX intensive program BloomTech (Lambda) Full-time 8-mo. UX curriculum July 2019 - March 2020

Bachelor of Architecture

College of Architecture & Environmental Design
Cal Poly, San Luis Obispo

CSU International Programs Architecture & Italian Full academic year Florence, Italy

Credentials

LEED Accredited Professional Licensed Architect, Colorado

Skills

UX / UI / Interaction design
Foundational UX research
UX strategy
Information architecture Systems
thinking
Flow diagramming
Wireframing & mockups
Prototyping & transitions
Presentation
Accessibility
Usability testing
Engineer hand-off
Project management
Client interface

Experience

Product Designer (UX/UI) - Consulting

SAN FRANCISCO & SAN CARLOS, CA | SEP. 2019 - PRESENT

Product UX/UI Designer | Architect

• Iterant: Strategized on early design for a three-sided circular economy marketplace providing incentives for enterprise-scale B2B reuse of goods in supply chains. Conducted foundational research & validation, laid out information architecture, advised on MVP site, mocked & prototyped critical screens for pitch decks.

nilpa.j@gmail.com · portfolio: jhaverini.github.io · linkedin.com/in/njhaveri

- Vox Pulmini: Created user flows, mockups, and UI prototypes for mobile app for participants to volunteer audio samples in support of affordable AI-based home healthcare management for children. Emphasized simplicity and intuitive ease-of-use.
- **Key Conservation:** Streamlined a lengthy onboarding flow for a mobile app enabling local biodiversity support through citizen science. Cocreated mockups, prototypes, and UI guidelines for app redesign. Proposed tests for validation and phased roll-out of features.
- HamiltonPay: Designed high-fidelity, mobile-first, responsive web app screens (marketing & platform) for B2C product demos for a payment tool serving small businesses, using smart contracts and intuitive, minimal form field entries. Adapted a design system based on Tailwind UI. Crafted prototypes to communicate transitions with team. Sole designer working cross-functionally as part of the founding team.
- **SpeakOut:** Simplified the overall website information architecture and content for a Bahraini English language school serving low-income students, to increase usability. Added mobile-first, responsive, simple registration flows to help resolve attendance and payment shortfalls.

Senior Project Architect / Project Manager - NELSON Worldwide

SAN FRANCISCO, CA | 2014 - 2019 (FKA WK DESIGN GROUP)

From definition to functional use, designed and led workplace experience projects, specializing in startups and game design studios. Responsible for project management and client/consultant relations. Point-person for QA on all out-going work office-wide, from regulatory approvals to engineer hand-off, focusing on implementation (buildability), fire/safety compliance, accessibility, completeness, and consistency with design systems. Mentored junior staff.

Project Architect - HGA Architects & Engineers

SAN FRANCISCO, CA | 2008 - 2014

Conducted stakeholder interviews and met with user groups in sketch sessions to improve on workflows in healthcare environments. Translated feedback into

Nilpa K. Jhaveri

Tools

Figma / Sketch
Photoshop / Affinity Photo
Illustrator & InDesign
HTML & CSS
Familiar with VS Code
Familiar with Github
Miro / Lucidchart / Visio
SketchUp / 3D Studio VIZ
AutoCAD & Revit

Mentions

- Neonatal ICU, Kaiser San Diego² covered in "Tiny Miracle Baby Finally Big Enough to Go Home," CBS News 8 San Diego.
- Diamond Heights Residence¹ mentioned in <u>House Colors</u>, by Susan Hershman.
- Glen Park Remodel¹
 mentioned in <u>Big Ideas for</u>
 <u>Small Spaces</u>, by Sunset
 Books.
- American Institute of Architects "Small Firms Great Projects" Exhibits: Sea Ranch Residence & Studio¹ and Noe Valley Residence¹.

- 1 Designer, Veverka Architects
- 2 Proj. Designer, HGA Architects & Engineers

Product UX/UI Designer | Architect

nilpa.j@gmail.com · portfolio: jhaverini.github.io · linkedin.com/in/njhaveri

Experience (continued)

designs for iteration, prototyping, and implementation. Helped stakeholders visualize and prioritize planning, scoping, and feasibility of future improvements for projects ranging from clinics to city blocks. Managed office-wide staffing projections, working with other corporate office locations to balance staffing needs. Sustainability Council member for SF office.

Architectural Designer - Consultant - 2007-2008

SAN FRANCISCO, CA | 2008 - 2014

Collaborated on laboratory, manufacturing, corporate office, and custom single-family home projects with multiple design firms.

Associate Designer - Veverka Architects

SAN FRANCISCO, CA | 2000 - 2007

Identified & advocated for unique needs of end-users of single family homes, multi-unit condos, and small commercial spaces, from concept to execution to functional use. Crafted custom spaces and communicated technical & design specifications across disciplines, under apprenticeship to the principal architect. Arranged office learning sessions and started a green materials library for sharing insights on environmentally-friendly building materials.

Junior Designer - Anderson Brule Architects

SAN JOSE, CA | 1999 - 2000

Co-conducted end-user research, focus groups, visioning sessions, and community workshops for foundational groundwork for civic projects. Audited existing conditions and workflows, and identified end-user and stakeholder goals. Analyzed findings and created visual representations on which to base design solutions.

About Me

Practicing human-centered design for 10+ years for physical and digital interactions, with an emphasis on sustainability and social good. Serial half marathoner (will run for donuts). Healthcare system hacker, penetrating the bureaucracy. Lifelong learner with a passion for physical media: wood, glass, ceramics.